[Music]
I'm dr. Andy Galpin this is five minutes
is not wasting any time let's jump right
into how much fat protein and carbs you
should eat now
we'll start with fat here typically
we're gonna say somewhere between 20
maybe 30 up to 35% of your total
calories should be coming from fat now
keep in mind you've got about nine
calories per gram of fat which is over
twice that of carbs and protein so when
we look at your plate or your serving
size that typically means the amount of
fat needs to be about half the amount of
protein or fat in terms of on your plate
now I've got a separate video showing
you that especially if you compare that
to like vegetables so if you have a
giant piece of salad or giant salad it's
gonna be huge in physical size because
there's almost no calories in it where
the the butter or the oil or the you
know nuts that you're gonna add are
really small in size because they're
energy dense alright so from there you
probably want only about a third or so
of your calories that you're eating on
fat to come from saturated fat now more
recent evidence has shown that if you're
above this classic quote-unquote 10
percent number that you can see it's
probably just fine in fact that 10%
number is maybe not even strongly
scientifically justified that doesn't
mean that there is no issues at all of
fat and you should have six hundred
grams of saturated fat a day or anything
like that but it does probably mean if
you go a little bit over you're not
gonna get heart disease especially if
you're physically active and otherwise
healthy healthy if your weight is under
control and you don't have obesity like
that then you're probably really doing
okay there if not you do want to be
keeping close tabs on saturated fat
mostly just because that's a lot of
calories and we know just being
overweight itself is such a massive risk
factor for a number of diseases you
don't really need to go out on your way
to eat a lot of cholesterol so that
number can be fairly low but most
importantly if you think about the role
of fat in nutrition it's typically to
give you lots of energy and this is a
major benefit of it it's packed with
calories which is a good thing if we
want energy and so by the same token I
believe is it is the easiest macro
nature it's one of the two easiest ones
with carbs to adjust with your goal so
are you training to maximize muscle are
you
trying to lose fat are you trying to
just have energy throughout the day no
I'll give you fair warning the classes I
teach and the athletes I work with are
almost always in the sport context so
all these slides you're seeing or not
the optimal diet for aging or cancer
prevention or somebody who's sitting in
a computer all day I'm generally coming
at this from the perspective of you're
trying to maintain at least a little bit
of physical activity exercise or you're
trying to be a peak high-performing
athlete something like that right
another caveat here to the fat thing of
course you can go much higher in your
fat especially if you're on like a
modified ketogenic diet or a full-blown
ketogenic diet people can survive and
function quite clearly even lose fat on
much higher percentages I'm not saying
you can't I'm not saying you can't
perform this work so the higher
percentage I'm simply saying most the
time most the athletes I work with are
gonna land in this 20 to 30 percent
number or so moving on then to
carbohydrates like I said the primary
purpose of carbs and fat are to be there
to produce energy for movement for life
protein has a different rule and so
along with fat I do believe
carbohydrates are the ones you should
probably adjust the most when you're
changing your physical activity status
whether this means reduction in training
increase in training different type of
training recovery etc I try to lose
weight and so I'd like to have the
athletes I work with is somewhere in the
neighborhood of two to seven grams per
kilogram of body weight per day remember
you got about half the calories per gram
and carbohydrates so the volume on your
plate can be a lot higher most of the
time though five is a pretty good number
in terms of grams per kilogram body
weight if you think about somebody who's
70 kilograms that's 150 pounds we'll
just call it that if you're eating 2
grams per kilogram that's a hundred and
forty grams of carbs a day and that's
not much and honestly I do have athletes
that are around that weight range and
they do fine on 150 grams of carbs today
even high-performing ones some feel
terrible on honoring 50 grams I have
others that are in that same weight
range and they're like 400 grams of
carbs a day and they still will lose
weight and be super lean and so the
range is quite significant here if
you're in the middle of like at a crazy
endurance event we were you're running
you know seven hours a day or something
like that for 5 or 10 or 50
a straight you see you can see people
get as high as 15 grams per kilogram
body weight which is crazy we start
talking kilo grams of total carbs are
dead but those are pretty abnormal right
so for the most of us we're going to
land in this range I have listed here
now we don't exactly know why but for
some buddies and females seem to need a
little more carbohydrate than than men
we have some hypotheses but it seems to
be pretty true whether or not we
understand why in terms of added sugar
you want about less than ten or so
percent of your total amount of
carbohydrates coming from added sugar
now please go watch some of my other
videos on what sugar really is before
you jump to conclusions here cuz most of
you think either sugars often for you or
you don't understand what sugar is and
so you do things like avoid fruits and
vegetables that's not what we're talking
about when I say less than ten percent I
mean added sugar I don't really use it
at all personally and I use it pretty
sparingly with even with athletes but I
will use it to its advantage what I need
with an athlete so fruits are fine all
that stuff is different those comets
carbohydrates they don't count is added
to sugar and then like I said
carbohydrates are the ones we will
adjust pretty rapidly and pretty easily
when we have a change in physical
activity different part of our season
before or five after five competition
and etc so that being said we can round
out things by talking about protein you
can see the different numbers here based
on kind of different training goals and
populations but really if you just put
everybody at 1.5 grams per kilogram per
day they're probably just fine if you
like the pounds version that's about a
gram protein per pound of body weight or
a little bit less so that 70 kilogram
person at 1.5 would be in the
neighborhood of 110 grams of protein per
day you can go a little bit higher now
honestly I don't I don't come up to much
and if you're wondering where to go it
typically recommend go higher rather
than lower okay you can get away with a
lot now I have separate videos on all
three of these macronutrients so if you
want 25 minutes of just protein or carbs
your fat you can go watch those videos
you want more detail about types of
carbs and types of fat and things like
that all those are available in those
other videos Oh
lastly here with our protein you
probably want someone that I knew
neighborhood of about Punk for g/kg of
protein per feeding right and that'll
get you to your total I want to leave
here on just a little bit of a teaser so
you can see that I'm actually a fan and
I've been kind of looting to this the
entire time of modifying and
manipulating our protein and carbs and
fats depending on what we're going after
what our training goal is etc and so
this is a really important concept that
I'm making a video for right after this
called period is nutrition so go check
that out if you want to hear more about
how we do this there's a lot of ways to
go about it and I'll explain those in
that video from now hopefully this
helped share it with your friends
[Music]